[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：承诺，非常好的核心。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Promises, pretty good at their core.
但是有很多抽象的东西是缺失的。
But there's an awful lot of Abstractions that were missing.
抽象是我们用来制造更高层次的强大工具之一
And Abstractions are what are one of the powerful tools that we use to make higher
和更高阶的模式，让我们的代码越来越有表现力。
and higher order patterns that let us be more and more expressive with our code.
我想和你谈谈几个抽象的是第一对夫妇
I want to talk to you about a few Abstractions is the first couple
是直接内置在浏览器中的Promise API中的东西。
are things that are built in directly into the promise API in the browser.
然后，我们将讨论通过第三方提供给我们的其他抽象
Then we'll talk about other Abstractions that are available to us through third
使用其他抽象在承诺的基础上包装和构建的party和库。
party and libraries that wrap and build on top of promises with other Abstractions..
我们可以讨论的第一个是Promise.all。
The first one we can talk about is Promise.all.
承诺，一切都需要一系列的承诺。
Promise,all takes an array of promises.
如您所见，您有一系列即将到来的承诺
As you can see, you have an array of promises that are coming
从这些doTask方法中，doTask1a、1b和1c。
from these doTask methods, doTask1a, 1b and 1c.
现在它要做的显然是所有这些函数
Now what it's going to do is obviously all of those functions
这意味着他们都在做出承诺。
are being call which means they're all producing promises.
我们可以想象，这就像三个独立的Ajax调用
We can imagine that that's like three independent AJAX calls
一下子就发生了。
happening all at once.
然后我们将等待所有这些完成
And then we're going to wait for all of those to finish and
您会注意到，我们得到了这些结果的数组，通过第6行传递给我们。
you'll notice that we get an array of those results, passed into us on line 6.
结果数组，将具有每个结果的数组
There array of results, will have the array of results from each of those
承诺在原始数组中列出的顺序。
promises in the order they were listed in the original array.
不管他们完成的顺序是什么，
Regardless of what order they finish in,
它们处于可预测的顺序，即请求顺序。
they're in a predictable order which is request order.
这让我们可以说，我不想只等一个承诺。
This is allowing us to say, I don't want to just wait for one promise.
我有三个需要同时发生。
I've got three that need to happen in parallel.
然后我需要等待他们全部完成，然后再继续。
And then I need to wait for all of them to finish before moving on.
你注意到了Promises.所有人都给了我们一个当时[INAUDIBLE]的承诺
You notice the Promise.all is giving us a promise which were then [INAUDIBLE]
离开6号线。
off of on line 6.
以及我们从先前的承诺中得到的完成结果，
And what we're getting as the completion result from that previous promise,
是所有结果的数组，而在这里我只是一个愚蠢的插图
is an array of all the results and here I'm just a silly illustration
我正在对这三个结果执行Math.max。
I'm doing Math.max across those three results.
我们可能是任务1a，1b和
We might have been task 1a, 1b and
1C可能已经生成了一些随机数。
1c might have been to generate some random number.
我们将要求生成的三个数字中的最大值
We're gonna ask for the maximum of the three numbers that was generated and
然后返回
then return and
将其传递给doTask2，然后返回一个我们当然可以更改的承诺。
pass that in to doTask2 and that returns a promise which we can of course change.
我们在这里提出的观点是，承诺链中的每一步都可以作为
The point that we're making here, is that each step in a promise chain can be as
简单的，链接在另一个承诺中，可以简单的像直接的
simple as, chaining in another promise, can be as simple as just an immediate
我们返回的值，或者可能是更复杂的值，
value that we return or it could be something more complex,
我们在这里看到的像Promise.call这样的高阶抽象。
a higher order abstraction like a Promise.call that we see here.
我们用老式的计算机科学术语来描述这个，我们称之为门。
Old school computer science terminology we use for this we call this a gate.
每当你有多件事发生时，
Whenever you have multiple things happening,
你不知道他们会按什么顺序完成，但是
you do not know what order they're gonna finish in, but
所有这些都需要在继续前完成，我们称之为“门”。
all of them need to finish before moving on, we call that a gate.
这里的API是Promise.all，但您可以将其视为一个gate。
The API here is Promise.all but you can think of that as a gate.
如果这三个承诺中的任何一个造成拒绝，
Now if any one of those three promises creates a rejection,
最主要的问题就是我们在六号线上用链子锁住的那个，
the main problem the one that we're chaining off of on line six,
主要承诺立即被拒绝。
that main promises immediately rejected.
所以.all要求成功完成。
So .all requires successful completion.
你可以想到一个抽象，我不关心成功完成，
You could think of an abstraction where I don't care about successful completion,
我只需要他们所有人都以积极或消极的方式结束。
I just need all of them to finish either positively or negatively.
这将是一个不同的抽象。
And that would be a different abstraction.
你可以开始认为我们实际上有很多不同的抽象概念
You can start to think there is actually quite a few different abstractions that we
可以发明。
can invent.
你可能会发明一个抽象概念，就像我希望在第一个抽象概念出现时得到通知一样
You might invent an abstraction like I want to be notified when the first one
完成或当第一个完成或失败时。
finishes or when the first one finishes or fails.
我刚才提到的那个抽象，就是
And that abstraction, the one I just mention, which is
当有人完成或失败时，我希望得到通知，这称为比赛。
I want to be notified whenever somebody finishes or fails, that's called a race.
我们还有一个名为Promise.race的实用程序，它接受一系列承诺。
We also have a utility called Promise.race, takes an array of promises.
它的定义是说，我将等待任何解决方案，无论是
And its definition is to say, I'm going to wait for any resolution, whether that's
实现或拒绝，任何这些承诺的解决方案，
a fulfillment or a rejection, any resolution of any of these promises,
谁先越过终点线谁就赢，并且
whichever one crosses the finish line first wins, and
其他人都被忽略了。
everybody else gets ignored.
这就是Promise.race的意义所在。
That's what Promise.race is about.
这里我展示了一个超时习语，因为我们之前没有回答。
Here I'm showing a timeout idiom, because we didn't answer earlier.
我有点掩饰了，
I kind of glossed over it,
希望你会问或者至少记住这一点。
hoping that you would either ask or at least remember at this point.
我们没有问，好吧，如果我的承诺永远不会得到解决会发生什么？
We didn't ask, well, what happens if my promise never gets resolved?
你处理这件事的方式就是我们处理任何可能
The way you handle that is the way we handle any asynchronous task that may
永远不会完成，这就是为它设置一些最大超时。
never complete, which is to set up some maximum timeout for it.
在这里，我所做的是我在第4行有p代表承诺，我
Here, what I'm doing is I've got p on line 4 representing the promise that I
关心。
care about.
然后我在第5行创造了另一个承诺，我其实并不关心，
And then I'm creating another promise on line 5, which I don't really care about,
它只是被设置成一个定时炸弹，三秒钟后，它就会被拒绝。
it's just set up as a time bomb, that after three seconds, it rejects.
在这种情况下，将会发生两件事中的一件。
One of two things is going to occur in this scenario.
要么我的承诺在三秒钟内完成，然后
Either my promise is going to finish in less than three seconds, and
我将得到它的结果，然后转到第11行，在第12行成功，或者
I'm going to get its result, and move on to line 11, with a success on line 12, or
拒绝承诺将首先完成，在这种情况下，另一个承诺，
the rejection promise is going to finish first, in which case the other promise,
不管它有没有完成，我们都会忽略它，并且
whether it ever finishes or not, we're going to ignore it, and
我们将移到第13行，因为这是一个承诺拒绝。
we're going to move to line 13, because this was a promise rejection.
我们将处理超时错误。&gt；&gt；扬声器2：如果发生超时，
We're going to handle a time out error. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: If the time out happens,
最初的承诺发生了什么，它是被垃圾收集了，还是
what happens to the original promise, does it get garbage collected, or
凯尔：是的。
does it- &gt;&gt; Kyle: Yes.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：留下来？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Stay around?
它可能会被冲走。凯尔：是的。
It would potentially get flushed. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Yep.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的，因为没有
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay, cuz there's no
不再引用它了。凯尔：是的，是的。
reference to it anymore. &gt;&gt; Kyle: Yep, yep.
Promise.race丢弃任何东西，一旦完成，
Promise.race throws away anything, once it finishes,
它丢弃了所有的引用。&gt；&gt；Kyle：[咳嗽]现在这不是
it throws away all its references. &gt;&gt; Kyle: [COUGH] Now this is not
这是一段非常优雅的代码，每次你想让承诺超时都要编写。
a terribly graceful piece of code to write every time you wanna time out a promise.
如果有一些高阶障碍物，那就太好了
That would be nice if there was some higher order obstruction for
计时承诺，事实证明是有的。
timing out promises, and it turns out there is.
几乎每个Promise库都有超时承诺的东西，并且
Virtually every promise library out there has something for timing out promises, and
从被子里出来，他们做的事情大体上就像我说的或者
out of the covers they're doing something roughly like what I'm talking about or
基本设置比赛&gt；&gt；Kyle：Promise.all和
setting up a race basically &gt;&gt; Kyle: Promise.all and
PROMISE.RACE使用浏览器中的API进行本机转换。
Promise.race shift natively with the API that comes in the browser.
但我们已经可以开始了，你的一些大脑可能已经开始思考了，
But we can already start, and some of your brains may already start to be thinking,
那么这个抽象呢，这个抽象呢？
what about this abstraction, what about this abstraction?
就像我只关心第一个
What about the one where it's like I only care about the first
一人成功越过终点线。
one to successfully cross the finish line.
我们可能会打电话，而不是称那是我们可能首先称之为的比赛。
We might call instead of calling that a race we might call that first.
这有一个抽象，库提供了这些抽象。
There's an abstraction for that and libraries provide those abstractions.
如果我只关心最后一个，最后一个赢了或者我们可以叫.last。
What if I only care about the last one, last one wins or we could call .last.
如果我想知道他们都被拒绝了怎么办。
What if I want to know that all of them rejected.
这是Promises的反面。所有人，而不是所有人都成功了，
It's the inverse of Promise.all, instead of all of them succeeding,
我想知道他们所有的拒绝。
I want to know of all of them reject.
我们可以称之为.没有这样我们就可以开始发明
We could call that .none so we could start to invent
几十种不同的抽象可以帮助我们，这些抽象成为乐高
dozens of different abstractions that can help us and these abstractions become Lego
我们构建更复杂的流量控制中心的构建块。
building blocks that we build our more complex flow control center.
我们链中的每个步骤都可以是这些抽象步骤之一，而不是
Every single step in our chain can be one of these abstracted steps instead of
只是一个单一的，如果那样的话，某种抽象。
just a single, if then sort of abstraction.
你想要寻找那些共同的抽象和
You want to look for those common abstractions and
就像在函数式编程中一样使用它们
use them just like in functional programming you wanna look for
像地图和减少和发展一种不重新发明轮子的本能，
things like map and reduce and develop an instinct for not reinventing the wheel,
但是使用已经发明的轮子并且知道它是如何工作的。
but using the wheel that's already been invented and knowing how it works.
你想围绕承诺抽象发展同样的本能。
You want to develop that same instinct around promise abstractions.
与其试图发明自己的模式，不如寻找那些已经
Rather than trying to invent your own patterns, look for ones that have already
坚固耐用。&GT；&GT；Kyle：好的，
been established and well worn. &gt;&gt; Kyle: All right,
更多关于承诺的阅读，我承诺你，双关语。
more reading about promises, I promised, I promised you, pun unintended.
我之前答应过你我写了一大堆关于这个的东西，
I promised you earlier that I had written a bunch about this,
顶部的这个链接是我写的五篇博文系列中的第一篇。
this link at the top link is the first in a five part blog post series that I wrote.
它很长，都是关于承诺的。
It's pretty long, all about promises.
我还谈到了错误处理和其他各种各样的事情。
And I talk about error handling and all kinds of other things.
我说的是可取消的承诺。
I talk about cancelable promises.
都在里面。
It's all in there.
如果你想深入阅读承诺，那是一个博客文章系列。
If you wanna read about promises in depth, that's a blog post series.
我在这本书的系列中广泛地写过承诺，包括异步和
I've written about promises extensively in the book series, both in the Async and
性能手册，以及ES6书籍，所以
performance book, as well as the ES6 books, so
那里有很多关于他们的书。
there's plenty to read there about them.
如果你想使用直接本地化的承诺
And if you want to use promises in straight up native
在旧浏览器中使用多填充方式的表单，但是
form in a polyfill fashion that is to use them in older browsers but
在没有附加物或任何东西的地方使用它们。
use them where there's no additions or anything.
我为承诺写了一个多填充，叫做NATIVE-PROMANE-ONLY。
I wrote a polyfill for promises called native-promise-only.
那里大约有十几个这样的复合填充物。
There are about a dozen or so of this polyfills out there.
关于寻找有希望的多填充材料，有一句话要小心。
One word of caution on looking for promise polyfills.
让我感到困扰的是那里有相当多的图书馆
Something that kind of bothers me is that there's quite a few libraries out there
它们声称是Promise PolyFill，实际上它们是Promise库，
which claim to be promise polyfills, really what they are promise libraries,
这在规范之上添加了一堆额外的东西，添加了一堆额外的助手。
that add a bunch of extra stuff on top of the spec, add a bunch of extra helpers in.
我反对添加帮助者吗？
Am I against adding helpers?
绝对不行。
Absolutely not.
我即将向您展示我编写的一个库，它添加了一堆助手。
I'm about to show you a library that I wrote that adds a bunch of helpers.
我是图书馆助手的超级粉丝，因为我们有很多事情要做
I'm a big fan of library helper's because there's a lot of stuff we want to do
带着承诺。
with promises.
我不喜欢他加了一堆帮手
Well I'm not a fan of his adding a bunch of helpers and
然后自称是多面体，因为多面体应该是无关紧要的
then claiming to be a polyfill, because a polyfill is supposed to be nothing but
规范符合性。
the specification compliance.
没有偷工减料，没有增加额外的东西和
No cutting corners, no adding extra stuff and
外面有一堆图书馆，它们有点走捷径，
there's a bunch of libraries out there that sort of cut some corners and
添加一些额外的东西，并且仍然称自己为PolyFill。
add some extra things in, and still call themselves polyfills.
在寻找它的时候要小心。
Be cautious about looking for that.
你可以相信本能的承诺只会
You can trust that native promise only does nothing but
实现符合规范的Promise版本。
implement the spec compliant version of promise.